（地心：地壳→上地幔→下地幔→外核→内核）
（地球 很久很久以前）
进球！
Goal!
《冰川时代4：大陆漂移》
什么声音，艾丽，你听见了吗？
What was that? Ellie, did you hear that?
我听到了，曼尼，别管了，远着呢
I heard it, Manny. Whatever it is, it's miles away.
桃桃，你还好吗？
Peaches, are you all right?
她人呢？
Where is she?
小孩可都是喜欢睡懒觉的
No teenager is ever up early.
你又没关她禁闭，“典狱官”
Easy warden, she's not on lockdown.
你们这两个叔叔该看紧点！
You two were supposed to be responsible uncles!
咋了？桃桃15到20分钟前还在啊
What? I didn't see Peaches sneak off maybe 15 or 20 minutes ago.
她可能和路易斯去瀑布那儿了
Or that she went with Louis to the falls.
瀑布？那些小混混出没的地方？
The falls? Where the delinquents go?
别担心，去那儿玩的只是些孩子
Relax, it's just where the kids hang out.
不不，这可是叛逆的不归路
No, no, it's a gateway hangout.
先是去瀑布那儿，然后是穿鼻洞…
First it's the falls, then she's piercing her trunk…
接下来就要染上莓瘾了
and the next thing you know, she's addicted to berries.
曼尼，你反应过度了
Manny! You are overreacting.
孩子总要长大
She's not going to be your little girl forever.
我知道，所以我才担心
I know. That's what worries me.
快来！
Come on!
路易斯！
Louis!
你就不能钻出脑袋，享受享受地面上的乐趣？
Would you get your head out of the ground for once and try to have a little fun?
身为鼹鼠，我本就该埋头地下
I'm a molehog. My head's supposed to be underground.
冒死陪你去邂逅小帅哥，可不是我的乐趣
And my idea of fun isn't risking death so that you can meet some cute mammoth.
伊森不只是帅，是性感
Ethan isn't cute. He's hot.
再说了，你也不能一辈子都那么循规蹈矩
Besides, you can't spend your whole life playing it safe.
- 我想我会的 - 爸爸？
- I know I would. - Dad?
你没必要生气
There's no reason to be mad.
你知道我不喜欢你去瀑布那儿
You know how I feel about you going to the falls.
尤其是独自一人
Especially alone.
她不是独自一人，先生
She's not alone, sir.
你不作数，小样
You don't count, Weiner.
你说的没错，我就是这么微不足道，谢谢
Yes, there's my place, and you just put me in it, thank you.
走吧，女儿
Come on, young lady.
回家了，这次我会看牢你
We're going home where I can keep an eye on you.
那我是等在这，还是…
So, should I just wait here, or…
你吓不倒我的，大自然母亲！
Yeah, you don't scare me, Mother Nature!
任何变故，我都能应付自如
There's nothing you can throw at me that I can't handle.
我想快到了
I think we're almost there!
最好是！我刚把方向盘拧掉了
We had better be! I just lost the steering.
有人看到珍珍吗？该给她喂饭了
Has anyone seen Precious? Lt's her feeding time.
妈！奶奶又在叨叨她那只死掉的宠物了
Mom! Granny's talking about her dead pet again.
爪子甩起来，各位！
Hey, paws up, everybody!
放下来，叔叔，求你了！胳肢窝好臭
Paws down, Uncle, please! That is nasty.
当心点，米尔顿，你会伤着人的！
Be careful, Milton, you're going to hurt somebody!
坏猫猫！
Bad kitty!
有岩石！
Rock!
好吧，那到底什么时候，我才能出去和男孩子约会？
Okay, so tell me, when exactly will I be allowed to hang out with boys?
得等我咽气，之后三天，彻底死翘翘了才行
When I'm dead, plus three days. Just to make sure I'm dead.
曼尼，你没事吧？
Manny, are you okay?
从我脸上…滚下去！
Get off… my face!
真有趣，现在，我该先吃谁呢？
That was fun. Now, who should I eat first?
不不不！
No, no, no!
霉叔叔！真的是你吗？
Uncle Fungus! Could that really be you?
抱歉，抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
爸妈！
Mom, Dad!
马歇尔！
Marshall!
- 嘿！ - 奶奶？
- Hey! - Granny?
这个南瓜可以摘了！
This pumpkin's ripe for picking!
我的一家子
My whole familia.
看见没？他仍然会拥抱他的父母
See? He still hugs his parents.
从没想过还能再见到我的小宝贝，我们到处找你
I never thought I'd see my little baby again. We've been searching everywhere for you.
你们找过我？
You have?
我就知道！我就知道！我没被抛弃！
I knew it, I knew it! Deep down, I knew I wasn't abandoned!
不对，我们是抛弃你了
That's incorrect. We totally abandoned you.
但我们还是想你的，对吧？
But we always missed you. Right?
对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我们也知道希德想见他可怜的亲奶奶…
And we just knew Sid would want to see his poor, dear Granny…
最后一面
before her time is up.
我会给你们送葬，在你们坟墓上起舞
L'll bury you all and dance on your graves.
看她多憔悴
So frail.
她老是吵着要你做伴呢，希德
And she can't wait to spend time with you, Sid.
是的，奶奶，奶奶？
Oh, yeah, Granny? Granny?
- 奶奶 - 从来就不让我玩个痛快
- Granny. - I never get to have any fun.
带她去看看你的洞穴，让她休息下
Why don't you show her your cave? Yeah, she could use a nap.
好的，我有好多话要跟你说
Boy, there's so much to tell you.
自从上次见到你之后，发生了很多事
A lot has happened since the last time I saw you.
没兴趣
Not interested.
我们在冰川时代和恐龙搏斗
But we fought dinosaurs in the lce Age.
这事儿虽然离奇，但挺激动人心的
It didn't make sense, but it sure was exciting.
终于摆脱这个疯老太婆了！快走！
We got rid of the crazy bat! Let's go!
等等！你们不能就这么走了
Whoa, whoa, whoa! You can't just leave.
希德会崩溃的
Sid will be crushed.
抱歉，亲爱的，老家山崩地裂了
Sorry, cookie, things are breaking apart back home.
所以我们得搬去内陆，奶奶是个大累赘
So, we're headed inland. And Granny is just dead weight.
- 再见 - 快走，快走！
- See you. - Mush, mush!
给你们提个醒，她有点神志不清！
And warn the community. She tends to wander!
得，怪不得希德也总是疯疯癫癫
Well, that explains a lot about Sid.
爸，妈，奶奶的假牙在你们那儿吗？她找不到
Mom, Dad, do you have Granny's teeth? She can't find them.
嘿！你能帮我嚼嚼吗？
Hey! Can you chew this thing for me?
伙计们？他们人呢？
Guys? Where is everyone?
我来处理
L'll handle this.
希德？
Sid?
你的家人被一颗小行星砸没了，节哀
Your family was wiped out by an asteroid. Sorry.
什么？
What?
迭戈要说的是…
What Diego is trying to say is…
他们走了
they left.
他们来找你，只是想让你照顾奶奶
They only wanted to find you so you could take care of Granny.
拜托，什么样的变态家庭会随便抛弃自己的奶奶？
Come on, what kind of sick family would ditch their Granny on someone?
真是太疯狂了，真是…
That's just crazy. That's just…
太像…
That's just…
…我的家人了
…my family.
起码你还有奶奶，对吗，伙计？
At least you still have Granny. Right, buddy?
嗯，奶奶，奶奶？
Yeah, Granny. Granny?
奶奶？
Granny?
以她这把年纪，跑得可真够快的
Wow. For an old girl, she moves fast.
- 奶奶？ - 奶奶
- Granny? - Granny.
奶奶？
Granny?
出来，别躲了！
Come out, come out wherever you are!
出来吧，奶奶
Come on, Granny.
奶奶，我这有梅干噢！
Here, Granny, Granny. I have prunes for you!
帮你嚼好了噢！
Just the way you like them!
别让我看到
I don't want to see that.
噢，不
Oh, no.
万一被你爸发现怎么办？我外强中干的！
What if your dad finds out? I'm not as tough as I look!
等等，你听见了吗？
Wait, do you hear that?
来呀！
Go long!
酷！
Cool!
嘿，瞧，那是伊森
Hey, look, there's Ethan.
耶，伊森！
Yeah, Ethan!
你真棒，帅哥！
You go, boy!
真不错
That was nice.
耶！
Yeah!
看到没，有乐子，没危险
See? Fun, no danger.
看我的！
Check me out!
- 我肯定他没事 - 我绝对有事！
- I'm sure he's fine. - I'm completely not fine!
你不是吧！太疯狂了！
You did not just do that! That was crazy!
很好
Nice.
耶！
Yeah!
他是不是很完美？
Lsn't he perfect?
“完美”，说得过头了吧，也就“差不多”
"Perfect". It's such a strong word. Maybe "adequate".
我们在跟踪谁？
Who are we stalking?
这是伊森吗？我猜是他
Ls it Ethan? I bet it's Ethan.
- 嘿，小样 - 你们在这干嘛？
- Hey, Weiner. - What are you guys doing here?
曼尼让我们盯紧你
Manny told us to keep an eye on you.
- 但不能让你发现 - 在任何情况之下
- But not to let you see us. - Under any circumstances.
蠢死了，蠢死了，蠢死了
Stupid, stupid, stupid.
好了，我要上了，我看起来还行吗？
Okay, I'm going for it. Do I look okay?
路易斯？
Louis?
你岂止是“还行”
"Okay" doesn't even begin to cover it.
路易斯，你是我最好的朋友！
Louis. You're the greatest friend ever!
是啊
That's me.
伊森，你好，我是桃桃，你呢？
Hi, Ethan, my name's Peaches. What's yours?
我这是干嘛？随意点，就…
What am I doing? Okay, just be cool, just be…
不！
No!
那招厉害！
Yeah. That's intense!
痛死我了！
This hurts so much!
不不不！
No! No! No!
讨厌，她就是那个和负鼠一样胆小的怪象
Gross. It's that weirdo who chills with possums!
发生什么事了？
What just happened?
不！伊森，真抱歉
Oh, no! Ethan, I am so sorry.
哇哦，你近看更帅了
Wow, you're even better-looking up close.
太帅了，我是说…
Phenomenal. I mean…
你有个双胞胎姐妹？
You have a twin sister?
我打扰到你们了吗？
Am I interrupting something?
- 爸爸！ - 糟糕，好吧…
- Dad! - Oh, boy. Okay…
抱歉，让我…
Sorry, if I just…
- 等下，不对，你往左边 - 往后一点
- Wait, no, you go left. - Just move back a bit.
你！离我女儿远点
You! Keep away from my daughter.
- 爸爸… - 还有你，你被禁足了！
- Dad… - And you, you're grounded!
- 但我什么也没… - 禁足！
- But I didn't do… - Grounded!
好衰
Loser alert.
哎哟，那就是她爸爸
Ouch, that's her dad.
说真的，太丢脸了
Seriously, that's embarrassing.
真是怪胎
What a freak.
桃桃！
Peaches!
桃桃，别这样，我们聊聊
Peaches, come on. Let's talk about this!
你怎么能当着我朋友的面给我难堪？
How could you embarrass me in front of my friends?
你故意去你不该去的地方！
You deliberately went where you weren't supposed to!
你不能控制我的生活！
You can't control my life!
我在保护你！这是父亲的责任
I'm trying to protect you! That's what fathers do.
好吧…我希望你不是我爸爸
Well… I wish you weren't my father.
她只是心情不好，亲爱的
She's just upset, honey.
桃桃！这又不是世界末日
Peaches! Lt's not the end of the world.
哇噢，不好意思
Whoa. Excuse me.
我想这动静跟你没关系
I don't think that was you.
- 怎么回事儿？ - 不知道
- What was that? - I don't know.
待着别动
Stay there.
我过来
L'll come to you.
- 艾丽！ - 曼尼！
- Ellie! - Manny!
不！
No!
- 爸爸！ - 桃桃！回去！
- Dad! - Peaches, get back!
快点，爸爸！快！
Hurry, Dad! Hurry!
曼尼！
Manny!
- 迭戈！ - 你跳不过去的！
- Diego! - You never would have made it!
艾丽，当心后面！
Ellie, behind you!
什么情况？
What's happening?
去陆桥那儿！你们过了桥就安全了
Go to the land bridge! You'll be safe on the other side.
不，曼尼！不！
No, Manny! No!
我们在那里见！
L'll meet you there!
曼尼！不！
Manny! No!
艾丽，你得离开这，快走！
Ellie, you have to get out of here! Go! Go now!
- 妈妈！ - 回来！回来！
- Mom! - Get back! Get back!
爸爸！
Daddy!
好好活着！
Stay alive!
不管要多久，我都会找到你们的！
No matter how long it takes, I will find you!
妈妈，这都是我的错，如果我听…
Mom, this is all my fault. If I had just listened…
桃桃！这不怪你，好吗？
Peaches! This is not your fault, okay?
要是我再也见不到他呢？ 而我们最后一次见面就是吵架
What if I never see him again? And the last thing we did was fight.
你爸爸是我见过最坚韧顽强的猛犸象
Hey, your father is the toughest, most stubborn mammoth I've ever met.
他会回来找我们的，他保证过的
He'll come back for us. That's a promise.
快，帮我把它转向！
Come on! Help me turn this thing around!
大家，冷静点，别慌张！
Everyone, please, settle down. Don't panic!
等等，妈妈，路易斯呢？我们得找到他
Wait, Mom, where's Louis? We have to find him.
好吧，得快点
Okay, fast.
他们需要我，我们得回去
They need me! We got to get back.
兄弟，这家伙太大了，转不动 洋流正把我们往外推
Buddy, this thing's too big to turn. The current's pulling us out.
我妈曾说过，塞翁失马，焉知非福
You know, my mother once told me that bad news was just good news in disguise.
是她抛弃你之前说的吗？
Was this before she abandoned you?
没错
Yes, it was.
但重点是，虽然一时狂风暴雨
But the point being that, even though things look bad…
但风雨过后就会有彩虹…
there's a rainbow around every corner…
而且还会一帆风顺！
and nothing but smooth sailing ahead!
一帆风顺，希德？
Smooth sailing, Sid?
- 路易斯？路易斯？ - 路易斯？
- Louis? Louis? - Louis?
小样！小样！小样！
Weiner! Weiner! Weiner!
路易斯，你在哪？快，我们得走了
Louis where are you? Come on, we have to go.
路易斯？
Louis?
桃桃！
Peaches!
路易斯，你得跳下来
Louis, you have to jump.
不！你们快走吧
No! Go, save yourselves.
我们不会丢下你
We're not leaving without you.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
跳吧！
Jump!
所以我宁愿走地下
This is why I travel underground.
谢谢你回来找我
Thanks for coming back.
你说什么呢？不能抛弃朋友
What do you mean? You don't leave a friend behind.
很好，我们走吧
Great, let's go.
那堵墙会一直移动，压死我们
That wall is going to keep moving and crush us.
我们得去陆桥那儿
We need to get to the land bridge.
有什么问题？
Any questions?
说？
Yes?
你们用象鼻吸水的时候，有没有鼻屎味？
When you drink water through your trunk, does it taste like boogers?
没有
No.
呃，有时候有啦，快走吧！
Well, sometimes. Let's move!
眼睛一直盯着地平线
Just keep your eye on the horizon.
我找不到地平线
I can't find the horizon.
大螃蟹！
Holy crab!
抓紧我
Hold me.
要是我死了…
If I don't make it…
给我讨个老婆，告诉她我爱她
find me a wife, and tell her I love her.
我们还活着！
We made it!
来呀，大海，你就这点能耐？
Come on, ocean, is that the best you can do?
我说的对吗，兄弟？
Am I right, buddy?
风雨过后真的有彩虹！
Hey, there really is a rainbow around every corner!
桃桃！
Peaches!
你没事吧？
You okay?
我只是很担心我爸爸
I'm just so worried about my dad.
听着，我们一定会找到他
Listen, we're going to get to him.
照这速度，我们会一直赶在那堵墙前面…
At this pace, we'll stay ahead of the wall…
很快我们就会到达陆桥的
and we'll make it to the land bridge before you know it.
我们都会活下来的
We're all going to survive this.
好吧，也许他们不会，但其他人都会没事
Okay, maybe they won't. But everyone else, totally fine.
我们离家越来越远了
We're still heading away from home.
是啊，但我们活下来了，还有彼此相伴
Yeah, but we survived, and we still have each other.
事情可能会更糟，不是吗？
Things could be worse, right?
他总算说对了一次
For once, he's actually right.
我们战胜了暴风巨浪…
We made it through storms and tidal waves…
和各种凶恶的海鲜
and a vicious assortment of seafood.
他们还能出什么招？
What more can they hit us with?
我不想起来的时候，非得叫我起来
Trying to make me get up if I don't want to get up.
我想起来的时候，自然就会起来
If I want to get up I'd get up.
有人吗？
Hello?
什么…？
What the…?
天杀的，我还要睡觉呢！
Dagnabbit, I'm trying to sleep!
奶奶？你还活着！
Granny? You're alive!
见到你可真是太‘惊’喜了
And can we say how thrilled we are to see you?
嘿，胖子，不打算把我弄出去吗？
Hey, fats, you want to get me out of here?
嘿，快点
Hey, come on.
假装我是一块甜点，那样你就有动力了
Pretend I'm a dessert, that should motivate you.
难以置信，你就这么睡着，过了这场暴风雨？
I can't believe this. You slept through that storm?
彗星撞地球那次，我也照样睡着了
I slept through the comet that killed the unicorns.
谢谢你给我放的洗澡水，希德
Thanks for drawing my bath, Sidney.
- 奶奶，抓住我的爪子 - 没门
- Granny, grab my paw. - No way.
这可是我几十年来头一次洗澡
This is my first bath in decades.
说得没错
There's your proof.
快！谁来帮帮忙！
Quick! Somebody do something!
- 我抓住你了，奶奶 - 放开我！
- I got you, Granny. - Get off of me!
奶奶！
Granny!
你们这些混小子看什么呢？
What are you peeping toms all looking at?
就不能让我好好洗个澡？像盯烤肉一样盯着我看
A lady can't take a bath in peace? Eyeballing me like a rump roast.
母树獭平均寿命多长？
What's the life expectancy for a female sloth?
她肯定活得比我们久，对吗？
She'll outlive us all, you know that, right?
好人不长命，恶人活千年
Yeah, the spiteful ones live the longest.
这片海洋到底有多大啊？！
How big is this ocean?
到处都是水水水
Water, water, everywhere.
却一滴都不能喝
Nor any drop to drink.
也许除了这滴
Well, except maybe that drop.
有点…咸
That's a little… salty.
珍珍！妈妈叫你呢
Precious! Mommy's calling you.
珍珍！过来，宝贝
Precious! Come here, sweetie.
嘿，女士，你见到珍珍了吗？
Hey, lady, have you seen Precious?
如果你说的是，你一直在找的…
Lf you mean the imaginary, or perhaps deceased, pet…
那只想象的或已死的宠物，没，我没看见
that you keep searching for, no, I haven't.
大伙，快看
Guys, look.
有鸟的地方，就有岛屿，对吗？
Where there's birds, there's land, right?
鸟儿，飞过来
Hey, buddy, come here.
不，等等！飞回来
No, wait, wait! Come back.
回来！
Come back!
一大块肥肉啊，船长
Lt's a huge bounty, mon capitaine.
四名乘客，引颈待宰
Four passengers. Ripe for the taking.
一个很臭，一个很胖
One very smelly, and one very plump.
在我的海域？
In my ocean?
撞大运了啊
What a terrible turn of events.
我就爱撞大运
I love a terrible turn of events.
是我幻觉了，还是那块冰正向我们漂过来？
Am I hallucinating, or is that ice coming straight towards us?
是啊，正漂过来，听起来上面有动物
Yeah, yeah, it's coming. It sounds like there's animals on it.
好棒！我们得救了，得救了！
Yippee! We're being rescued, we're being rescued!
我听到了笑声
I hear laughter.
肯定是一艘派对游轮
Must be a party cruise.
他们看起来毛茸茸的
Hey, they look fluffy.
我要那个毛毛的大家伙
I get the big woolly one.
哇噢
Wow.
准备好把他们大卸八块，伙计们
Get ready to slice and dice, boys.
- 别吵，斜眼 - 嘿！
- Knock it off, Squint. - Hey!
等待船长指令
Wait for Captain's orders.
嘿，下面的！
Ahoy, down there!
你们真幸运
How lucky are you?
这一片海域常有海盗出没
You know these waters are infested with pirates.
对吧，孩儿们？
Right, boys?
我们有幸抢在他们之前找到你们
Glad we found you before they did.
肚黑船长来帮你们了
Captain Gutt, here to help.
那猴子可真好
You know, that's a nice monkey.
瞧，我们不想惹麻烦，我们只想回到大陆
Look, we don't want any trouble. We just need to get back to the continent.
大陆？那个大石子堆吗？
The continent? That pile of rubble?
我的家人在那，所以如果你能…
My family's there, so if you could just…
你的家人？真是温馨
Your family? That is so sweet.
但愿你跟她们告别过了，因为你已经回不去了
I hope you said goodbye, because there's no way back.
回得去的，你不记得了吗，船长？
Yes, there is. Don't you remember, Captain?
你可以驶去之型湾，然后顺着洋流回去
You can sail to Switchback Cove and catch the current back from there.
我这小脑袋，记得很牢的
It's like a steel trap, this noggin is.
万分感谢，福林先生
Thank you, Mister Flynn.
看吧？我就知道能回去
See? I knew there was a way home.
休想回去！
There is no home!
只能留在这
There is only here.
在这里，你的船归我所有
And here, your ship belongs to me.
进入战斗！
Battle stations!
扬起旗帜！
Fly the colors!
你们是投降，还是领教我的暴怒
Now surrender your ship or face my fury.
领教你的毛什么？
Or face your furry what?
不是“毛什么”，是“暴怒”！
Not "furry". Fury!
开火！
Fire!
打中猛犸赢大奖
Hit the mammoth, win a prize.
叮叮叮
Ding, ding, ding.
发射右舷炮
Fire the starboard cannons.
我就爱干这个！
I love this job!
希拉，活捉
Shira, fetch.
遵命，船长
Aye-aye, Captain.
你差点就成功了
You almost made it.
我不跟女人打
I don't fight girls.
因为你太弱了
I can see why.
肚皮跳
Belly flop.
希德！
Sid!
跳伦巴吧，小东西
Let's rumba, Tiny.
该睡了，大家伙
Lights out, big fella.
曼尼！
Manny!
你好
Hello.
嘿，兄弟
Hey, buddy.
欢迎参加派对
Welcome to the party.
让我们瞧瞧你会跳什么舞，跳啊，小奎特鱼！
Let's see what kind of moves you got. Dance, little Scrat fish!
尽情跳吧！
Dance your coconuts off!
欢快地跳
Happy dance.
瞧瞧他
Look at him.
我的战利品呢？有谁瞧见了吗？
Where's my bootie? Has anyone seen it?
老兄，就在你后面
Dude, it's right behind you.
哪，我的战利品在哪？
Where? Where's my bootie?
我看不到
I can't see it.
我就看到了你的大屁股
It's all I can see.
这是我度过的最美好的休假
This is a lovely vacation. Best I've ever had.
早上好，阳光帅哥
Morning, sunshine.
让我先伸出友谊之手
Let me be the first to extend the hand of friendship.
那是脚
That's your foot.
什么都瞒不过你，是吧？
Nothing gets by you, does it?
你想怎样？
What do you want?
我肯定你现在感到失落、害怕和迷惘
I bet you're feeling lost, scared, confused.
让我解释一下
Allow me to explain.
奏乐，孩儿们
Help me out, boys.
船长要唱小曲了！
Captain's going to sing a shanty!
一叶小舟，一路荡，一路漂
Here you are on a boat You're adrift, you're afloat.
你们迷失在茫茫大海
One might even say you're stuck.
我没有幸灾乐祸，我是要善意提醒
Well, I don't want to gloat But I would like to note.
你们很幸运
That you're in luck.
海上霸王大猩猩拯救了你们
You've been saved by the ape That rules these waters.
就别再想你的妻女了
So forget about Your wives and daughters.
大副，请向他们细数我的荣光
First Mate introduce me to them, please.
收到，肚黑船长
Aye-aye, Captain Gutt.
- 他庞大又恐怖 - 高雅却多毛
- He's the big and scary - Elegant yet hairy.
- 望而生畏 - 面皮发黑
- Fear-inspiring - Years from retiring.
- 打劫偷盗 - 剥皮香蕉
- Looting, stealing - Banana peeling.
当之无愧，海上霸王
Undisputed Master of the Seas.
哦天啊
Oh, jeez.
- 就是我 - 就是他
- That's me - 'Tis he.
好了，好了
Okay, okay.
我是灵长类海盗先驱，这些是我的敢死喽啰
I'm a primate pirate pioneer And these are my brave buccaneers.
他们也曾像你们一样，迷失了灵魂
All of whom were once Lost souls like you.
没错
It's true.
- 他拯救了我们 - 他救了我们的小命
- He rescued us - He saved our butts.
所以我们都欠他一命
For that we owe our lives to Gutt.
要是他饶你们不死
And assuming he doesn't kill you.
你们也欠他一命
You will owe him, too.
杀了他们？
Kill them?
我吗？不不
Me? No, no.
起码不杀这头有用的大块头猛犸
Well, at least not this very large, useful mammoth.
嘿，别碰我
Hey, hands off.
总之…
Anyway…
我们同乘一条船，全速前进
Here we are on a ship Moving at quite a clip.
一起穿梭于冰河之中
Through the ever-shifting ice.
一道航行吧
Come along on a trip.
- 暗示你哦 - 提示你哦
- That's a hint - That's a tip.
很好的建议哦
That's good advice.
在这下沉的世界，要活命就得学会抢劫
In a world that's going under To survive you must learn to plunder.
那正好是我的专长
Luckily that's my field of expertise.
他最棒
He's the best.
- 他抢劫偷盗 - 我们真的该走了
- He's a robbing, thieving - We really should be leaving.
- 舞刀弄枪 - 我们得走了
- Weapon throwing - We got to get going.
- 屠杀树獭 - 希望我们能留下来
- Sloth-slaying - Wish we could be staying.
当之无愧，毫无争议
Undisputed Uncontested.
- 这猴子就是 - 对，说的没错
- Monkey suited - Yeah, you guessed it.
海上霸王
Master of the seas.
省省吧
Oh, please.
- 就是我 - 就是他
- That's me - 'Tis he.
- 是谁？ - 是你
- It's who? - It's you.
考考你们而已
Just testing, I knew.
就是我
It's me.
唱的真好，船长
Good shanty, sir.
“肚黑船长”？是吗？
"Captain Gutt"? Really?
我也有点小肚子，但我不会拿这个当名字使
I have a little paunch, too, but I wouldn't name myself after it.
很搞笑，你真搞笑
That's funny. You're a funny guy.
但那不是我名字的由来
But that's not how I got my name.
是靠这个来的
These got me my name.
- 我没懂 - 不懂？
- I don't get it. - No?
好吧
Okay.
我给你演示一遍
Let me give you a visual aid.
我轻轻的按住这里
I just gently press here.
- 好痒 - 然后往下一划
- That tickles. - And go down like this.
然后你的内脏就全出来了
And then your innards become your outards.
我还是没懂
I still don't get it.
听着，就算我想加入，可一只猴子…
Look, as much as I'm tempted to join a monkey…
一只复活节兔子，还有一大包布丁…
the Easter Bunny and a giant bag of pudding…
我想还是算了
l'll pass.
没人能阻止我回到家人身边
No one's going to stop me from getting back to my family.
看我不把你的心肝挖出来，小子
I'm going to lambada with your liver, buddy.
别拦着我！
Let me at him!
要见家人，死路一条
That family is going to be the death of you.
大副，把累赘扔掉
First mate, jettison the deadweight.
遵命，船长，准备跳板！
Aye-aye, sir. Prepare the plank!
准备跳板！
Prepare the plank!
Preparing the plank!
什么，你想我走进水里？
What? You want me to walk into the water?
不行，我刚吃了东西 按规矩你们不能处死一个刚吃饱的人
I can't because I just ate less than 20 minutes ago, and you know the rule.
那只是传说
That's a myth.
好吧，只要安全就好
Okay, as long as it's safe.
- 等等！ - 谢天谢地
- Wait! - Thank goodness.
女人也扔掉
Dump the wench, too.
女士优先
Ladies first.
真懂事
Such a nice boy.
你怎么就不学着点，希德
Why can't you be more like him, Sidney?
奶奶，别！等等！
Granny, no! Wait!
曼尼
Manny!
把我弄到树藤那
Get me to the vine.
好的，知道了
Yeah, yeah, got it.
你们养的金鱼好丑
You all got some ugly goldfish.
加油，再过去点
Come on, a little more.
不！
No!
灭了那只猛犸
Extinct that mammoth.
加油，曼尼，狠狠踢他的猴屁股！
Come on, Manny, kick his monkey butt!
看看你
Look at you.
11吨的旱鸭子
Eleven tons of landlubber blubber.
我不是胖，是蓬松！
Hey, I'm not fat! I'm poufy.
可惜了，肥仔，本来我还想提拔你
Too bad, Tubby. I could have used you.
别做梦了，船长
Ain't going to happen, Captain.
我接住你了，奶奶
I got you, Granny.
快快，我们走
Giddy up, let's go, let's go.
谁有救生圈吗？
Does anyone have floaties?
不不！
No! No!
我的战利品！
My bounty!
他们弄沉了我们的战舰，我们怎么办？
They sunk our battleship. What are we going to do?
我们都会被淹死的
We're all going to drown.
你是海洋生物，白痴
You're a sea creature, you idiot.
说得对，船长
Good point, sir.
要我举白旗吗，船长？
Should I fly the white, captain?
不！
No!
等等，希拉哪儿去了？
Wait, what about Shira?
- 她能上哪儿去？ - 就是，她又能上哪儿去？
- What about her? - Yeah, what about her?
还有谁想来充“船长”？
Anyone else want to play "Captain"?
很好
Good.
快点，白痴，给我游
Now come on, blubber-brain. Swim.
喂！肚黑船长！福林！在吗？
Hey! Gutt! Flynn! Anyone there?
这里，抓住
Here, grab hold.
走开，我宁愿淹死
No, go away. I'd rather drown.
随你便了
Whatever the lady wants.
我说了不用你帮
I said I didn't need your help.
不客气，愿意屈尊加入我们这支老弱残兵吗？
You're welcome. So, care to join our scurvy crew?
两只树獭，一只猛犸和一只剑齿虎？
Two sloths, a mammoth and a saber?
你们这支队伍就是一个大笑话
You guys are like the start of a bad joke.
可就是我们救的你
And we saved you.
所以你才是笑点，猫咪
That makes you the punch line, kitty.
不许叫我“猫咪”
Don't call me "kitty."
好吧，我不叫…
Okay, I won't…
猫咪
Kitty.
他们要是接吻，我可要吐了
If they kiss, I'm going to puke.
什么？哦不
What? Wait, no.
我们到了吗？
Are we there yet?
我觉得我们永远也到不了
I don't think we're ever going to get there.
也许该休息一下
Maybe we should rest for a few hours.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安，艾丽
Night, Ellie.
我想你，爸爸
I miss you, Dad.
这样的奇景可真是难得一见啊
Well, that's something you don't see every day.
伊森！
Ethan!
你好！
Hi.
我故意这样下树的
I meant to do that.
我从没见过猛犸倒挂着睡觉的
I've never seen a mammoth sleep like that.
啥？我才不是在睡觉，倒挂有助我思考
What? No, this just helps me think.
促进大脑血液循环…什么的
It gets blood to the old noggin and away from the old… whatever.
好吧，还是有点怪
Okay, that's a little weird.
你还好吗，发生了这么多事？
So, how are you doing, you know, with all of this?
说实话，有点害怕
Honestly, a little scared.
好吧，是很怕
Okay, a lot scared.
我们熟悉的东西都没了
Everything we knew is gone.
是啊，我也很怕
Yeah, I was pretty scared, too.
也不是怕，是担心
I mean, not scared, but, like, concerned.
你明天想和我一块走吗？
Do you want to walk with me tomorrow?
一起忘掉这些烦恼
Try and get our minds off all this stuff.
你愿意和我一起走？
You want to walk with me?
今天早上你差点把我压扁
You did almost flatten me this morning.
我想，应该不会发生比这更糟糕的事了，对吧？
So, I figure it can't really go worse than that, right?
对
Yeah.
还有一件事
Just one thing.
也没什么大不了，但你最好别带上那只鼹鼠
It's totally no big deal, but you might want to lose the molehog.
路易斯吗？好的，没问题
Louis? Yeah, sure, not a problem.
哇
Wow.
有人很开心哦
Someone looks happy.
伊森很棒，对吧？
Ethan's great, isn't he?
宝贝，我知道你喜欢他…
Baby, I know you like this one…
但别为了别人改变自己，好吗？
but just don't let anyone change who you are, okay?
我知道
I know.
你上来吗？
You coming up?
我今晚就睡下面
I think I'm going to sleep down here tonight.
好的
Okay.
晚安，宝贝
Night, baby.
晚安，妈妈
Night, Mom.
晚安，爸爸
Good night, Dad.
帮我嚼嚼这个三明治
Hey, chew this sandwich for me.
奶奶，为什么家里人要抛弃我们，我们有错吗？
Granny, why didn't our family want us? What's wrong with us?
他们觉得我们一团糟，什么都做不对
They think we're screw-ups and we can't do anything right.
有老鼠！
It's a rat!
不！不！
No! No!
- 又搞砸了 - 希德！
- Screw up. - Oh, Sid!
靠这个我们回不了家
We'll never make it home on this thing.
在你弄翻我们的船之前，就该想到了，天才
Maybe you should have thought of that before you capsized our berg, genius.
我们得先脱身
Yeah, trying to escape.
- 窝囊废！ - 唠叨鬼！
- Wimp! - Whiner!
- 爱哭鬼！ - 陆地！
- Crybaby! - Land!
对，陆地！等等，啥？
Yeah, land! Wait, what?
不是说她，看那！
Not her. There!
陆地！
Land!
大家快划！快划！
Everyone paddle. Paddle!
食物！想死你了！
Food! I missed you so much!
看看我，都饿扁了
Look at me, I've wasted away.
好了，点心吃够了，我们得造个木筏
Okay, snack time is over. We got to build a raft.
曼尼
Manny.
希拉肯定很讨厌造木筏
Wow, Shira must really hate building rafts.
追上她，没她指路我们回不去
Go get her. She can help us get back.
希拉！
Shira!
逮到你了！
Gotcha!
哇！
Whoa!
放开我
Let go of me.
你想跑哪去？
Where do you think you're going?
哇！
Whoa!
之型湾
Switchback Cove.
回家的路
It's the way home.
不是吧
Oh, no.
你管这叫船？可悲的畜生！
You call this a ship you miserable runts?
你们这些小畜生，快干活
Yeah, you little runts. Get to work.
快点，你们这些没用的，连喂鲨鱼的象鼻虫…
Faster, you worthless, wormy sons of sorry excuses…
都抱歉的小臭屁虫！
for shark bait weevils!
- 他说的啥？ - 不知道
- What did he say? - I don't know.
日落之前把这艘冰船造好…
Now get this chunk of ice seaworthy by sundown…
否则把你们杀光！
or I will keelhaul the lot of you!
你们怎么想？
So what do you think?
四个字，愤怒管理
Two words, anger management.
我是说洋流
I'm talking about the current.
迭戈说的对，我们找到回家的路了
Diego's right. We found the way home.
太好了，可惜我们没有船
Yeah, that's great. Too bad we don't have a ship.
当然有，就在那
Sure we do. It's right there.
计划可真完美
Well, that's a flawless plan.
你们打算从一群海盗手里打劫一艘海盗船？
You want to pirate a pirate ship from pirates.
虽然我很不想这么说，但…
It pains me to say this, but…
- 我们的人质说的没错 - 这个嘛…
- our prisoner has a point. - Yeah, well…
伙计们，那些树都有耳朵
Guys. The trees have ears.
等等，也许我们能互相帮助
Wait a minute, maybe we can help each other.
小家伙，出来下
Hey, little fellas. Hey, come on out.
不不，没关系的，我们不会伤害你们
No, no, it's okay. We're not going to hurt you.
我们联合起来对抗海盗，怎么样？
How about you and us against the pirates, huh?
你们不知道我在说什么，对吗？
You got no idea what I'm saying, do you?
好吧，船，我要
Okay, ship, me want.
你当你是丛林英雄啊
Yeah, nice try Jungle Jim.
尽管嘲笑我吧，他懂的
Go ahead make fun. He got it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我来试试？
May I try?
请便
Yeah, knock yourself out.
好的，看好了
Okay, watch this.
八百标兵奔北坡，八百标兵奔北坡
Sick sloths sip broth, sick sloths sip broth.
好了！
Ta-da!
那都能懂？
That, they got?
好了，他们同意了
Yup, they're in.
很好，我们会救出你们的朋友，同心协力…
Great, we'll free your buddies and we can all work together…
再抢些战利品
to kick a little pirate booty.
别紧张，猫咪，给你水
Easy, kitty. Water.
喝点吧
You need it.
不用你可怜我
I don't need anything from you.
好吧，渴死吧，这样你就能倔强到底了
Fine, die of thirst. That will really show me.
等下
Wait.
我喝
L'll take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
你这句“谢谢”的语气，倒像是在说“去死”
You have a way of saying "thank you" that makes it sound like "drop dead."
我天赋异禀呗
Lt's a gift.
作为剑齿虎，你太温柔了
Well, you're pretty soft, for a saber.
不好意思，我那不是温柔
Excuse me, I am not soft.
我可是杀人不眨眼
I happen to be a remorseless assassin.
迭戈亲爱的！
Diego-poo!
我又给你做了个珊瑚项链
Hey, I made you another coral necklace.
他总是弄丢
He keeps losing them.
我想我开始理解为什么你不跟随虎群了
Yeah, I think I'm starting to get why you're not in a pack.
听着，我主动离开他们的，好吗？
Listen, I chose to leave my pack, all right?
恭喜啊，公主战士
Congratulations, warrior princess.
我也是
So did I.
- 真的？ - 咋了？
- Really? - What?
没什么，我能理解离开熟悉的一切…
Nothing, I just know how hard that is…
有多艰难
walking away from everything you know.
噢，太棒了，我们这是要促膝谈心吗？
Oh, great, are we going to braid each other's fur now?
哈哈，真搞笑
Funny. Really funny.
要我告诉你我之间的区别吗？
Can I tell you the difference between you and me?
是我就不会戴那条项链？
I wouldn't still be wearing that necklace?
不，也许我们都离开了虎群
No, we both might have wanted out of pack life…
但我并非单纯从一个群落改换到另一个群落
but at least I didn't trade one pack for another.
我得到的更多
I got something more.
是吗，那是什么？
Oh, yeah, what's that?
- 一个团队 - 有什么区别？
- A herd. - What's the difference?
我们互相照应
We have each other's backs.
肚黑船长也照应我，我是他的大副
Gutt has my back. I'm his first mate.
是吗？我可没瞧见肚黑船长派人来搜寻你
Really? Because I don't see Gutt sending out any search parties for you.
你打不赢他的
You know, you won't beat him.
你那个毛绒绒的大块头朋友？
Your big furry friend over there?
他不知道自己面对的是什么
He has no idea what he's up against.
是啊，但肚黑船长也不知道
Yeah, but neither does Gutt.
解开绳索，直到我们都上船了再松手
Unwind the binds, don't let go until we're all on board.
好了，我们需要每个人都准时完成任务，才能抢到船
Okay, we need precision timing from everyone to get that ship.
半品脱，你都准备好了，对吗？
Half-pint, you got your end covered, right?
我当你点头了，迭戈？
I'm going to take that as a "yes." Diego?
我会救出他的那些小朋友
L'll free his little friends.
希德和奶奶？
Sid and Granny?
松绑船只，长官！
Untie the ship, sir!
对，解开藤索，直到我们都上船了再松手
Right, unwind the vines, and don't let go until we're all on board.
我们都靠你了，希德，明白吗？
We're relying on you, Sid. You got that?
是的，全力以赴，长官
Yes, sir. Totally focused, sir.
别担心
Don't worry.
既然我们不用再看守希拉，事情简单很多
It'll be easy since we don't have to guard Shira anymore.
我们得行动了，马上
We need to move, now.
斜眼，封舱
Squint, batten down the hatches.
拉兹，起锚
Raz, hoist the anchor.
古普塔，扬起旗帜
And, Gupta, fly the colors.
没问题，船长
Of course, Captain.
我们起航复仇去，孩儿们
We're setting sail for vengeance, lads.
我爱复仇
I love vengeance.
船长！
Captain!
希拉！噢，见到你我就放心了！
Shira! Oh, what a relief!
我以为你死了
I thought we'd lost you.
那头猛犸，他和我一起被冲到这里
The mammoth. He washed ashore with me.
什么？他在这？
What? He's here?
你有没有咬住他，他有求饶吗？
Did you sink your fangs into him? Did he beg for his life?
没，剑齿虎抓住了我
No, the saber took me down.
你这个败寇
You're a failure.
我需要战士，手底下却尽是些猫咪和兔子
I need warriors, and all I have are kitty cats and bunny rabbits.
以及海豹和袋鼠
And a seal and a kangaroo.
去把剑齿虎干倒
You take the saber down, or you die trying.
不成功，则成仁
No excuses.
遵命，船长
Yes, Captain.
斜眼先生
Mr. Squint.
在，船长
Aye, sir.
现在你是大副了
You're first mate now.
就看我的吧，船长
Yo-ho-ho and a bottle of cool with me, Captain.
别挡道，剑齿虎，你现在得听我的
Out of my way, saber. You answer to me now.
肚黑船长，听着，他要来…
Gutt, listen, he's coming for the…
拿起武器，伙计们！
Grab your weapons, mates!
不是勺子，福林
Not the spoon, Flynn.
跟上！
Follow me!
上啊
Yeah, let's do this.
我来对付他！
Let me at him! Yeah!
小家伙们，没必要这样，真的
Guys, that's not necessary, really.
我也爱你们
I love you, too, yeah.
去船上，别搞砸，去船上，别搞砸
Get to the ship, don't screw up. Get to the ship, don't screw up.
- 松绳索 - 别放手
- Unwind the vines. - Don't let go.
松绳索
Unwind the vines.
别放…有果子！
Don't let… Oh, yummo!
希德，别吃！那是忘忧果
Sid, no! Lt's a lotus berry.
会让你全身麻痹的
It will paralyze you.
拜托，我很了解莓果的
Oh, please. I know my berries.
别…
Don't…
吞下去
swallow.
看，我没事，我最了解的，莫过于莓果了
See, I'm fine. If there's one thing I know, it's berries.
糟糕！
Uh-oh!
瞧我的！
Yeah, finally!
想尝尝复活节兔子的厉害？
Who's the Easter Bunny now?
- 成功了，他中计了！ - 快！
- It worked, he bought it! - Come on!
糟了！
No, no!
他们在声东击西
Lt's been a diversion.
我知道，我快要爆炸了
I know, I'm having a blast.
不是，尖脑袋，他们是要偷我的船
No, pinhead, they're stealing my ship.
一件事，希德，你就不能做好一件事？
One thing, Sid. You couldn't do one thing?
看看你
Look at you.
希德，你听得到吗？
Sid, can you hear me?
拜拜
Bye-bye.
说话啊，朋友
Say something, buddy.
抓住他们！
Let's get them!
我们走
Let's go.
船！
The ship!
快，得在它入海之前赶上！
Come on, we've got to catch it before it hits open water!
抱歉，我把你举高点
Sorry. All right, l'll hold you higher.
抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
说再见吧，猛犸！
Say adieu, mammoth!
再见
Adieu!
抱歉，朋友
Sorry, buddy.
我来了，希德
I'm coming, Sid.
我接住你了！接住了！
I got you! I got you! I got you!
我来找你了，猛犸
I'm coming for you, mammoth.
迭戈！
Diego!
快！
Come on!
快，跑起来！
Come on, move it!
你为什么这么做？
Why are you doing this?
你不明白，我没得选
You don't understand. I don't have a choice.
你不必过这样的生活，希拉
You don't have to live this way, Shira.
你和我们在一起会很安全
You'll be safe with us.
- 我们互相照应 - 迭戈！
- We take care of each other. - Diego!
我快撑不住了
I can't hold on much longer.
迭戈！
Diego!
和我们一起走吧
Come with us.
跟我走吧
Come with me.
你这是干吗？
What are you doing?
照应你
I've got your back.
再见了，香蕉崽！谢谢你的船！
So long, banana breath. Thanks for the ship!
不，他永远离开我们了
Oh, no, he's gone forever!
他在那
Oh! There he is.
上岸假结束了
Shore leave is over.
你们这帮懒骨头都给我上船
Get your sorry carcasses on board now.
肚黑船长，我能解释
Gutt, I can explain.
等一切结束了…
When this ends…
我要在墙上挂一张虎皮
l'll have a tiger's skin hanging on my wall.
不管挂谁的
I don't care whose.
那只猛犸抢了我的船…
That mammoth has taken my ship…
我的战利品…
my bounty…
还窃取了我手下的忠心
and now the loyalty of my crew.
我要灭了他…
I will destroy him…
和他所爱之物！
and everything he loves.
快来了，快来了
Wait for it. Wait for it.
太棒了
That was awesome.
我能问你们个事吗？
Can I ask you guys something?
你们俩怎么这么高兴？
How are you both so happy?
世界就快末日了，你们不担心吗？
Doesn't it weigh on you that the world might be ending?
我能告诉他我们的秘诀吗？
Can I tell him our secret?
过来，过来
Come here. Come here.
因为我们非常，非常缺心眼
We're very, very stupid.
难道你们真没有一丁点的担心…
But, still, you're not a teensy bit concerned about…
怎么讲呢，比如说迫在眉睫的死亡？
I don't know, say, imminent death?
哔
Beep.
我去找桃桃了
I'm going to go find Peaches.
大伙，这边，快，有捷径
Guys, over here. Come on, it's a shortcut.
你会喜欢的
You're going to love this.
来呀，姑娘们，一起来找点乐子吧
Come on, girls, let's have some fun.
哇！
Wow!
- 太酷了 - 就像翻了个倒栽葱
- This is so cool. - It's like we're upside down.
太惊人了
That is amazing.
诶嘿！
Echo!
你那鼹鼠朋友不在真可惜
Too bad your molehog friend isn't here, huh?
你们不是真的朋友吧？
You're not really friends with him, are you?
是啊，说清楚，桃桃
Yeah, come clean, Peaches.
你到底和那只奇怪的鼹鼠是不是朋友？
Are you friends with that awkward little rodent or not?
我想说…
I mean…
我和路易斯是一起玩过
Louis and I, we've hung out or whatever.
但我们并不是真正的朋友
But, no, we're not really friends-friends.
不是朋友？
Not friends?
路易斯！我…
Louis! I…
被发现了哦
Busted.
我知道了
Good to know.
路易斯，等等
Louis, wait.
他跑走的样子也很失败
He even runs away like a loser.
桃桃，别担心，你现在有我们了
Whoa, Peaches, don't stress. You're with us now.
担心太有压力了
Yeah, stress is so stressful.
是啊，妹子，要担心就担心你的发型吧
Yeah, girl, if you're going to stress about something, stress about your hair.
可不是嘛？我的头发就受不了这里的湿度
I know, right? This humidity, I can't stand it.
大伙，我们该离开这里
Guys, we should get out of here.
开玩笑吧？这太赞了！
Are you kidding? This is epic!
快走！
Go! Go! Go!
好
Yeah!
多刺激啊？
How sick was that?
太疯狂了
Yo, that was insane.
桃桃，放轻松，好好玩
Hey, Peach, loosen up! Have some fun.
好玩，那叫好玩？我要走了
Fun, you call that fun? I'm out of here.
别这样，你真的想回去…
Come on, do you really want to go back…
把我们抛下，和你那个怪鼹鼠朋友玩？
to hanging with a weird molehog freak and give all of this up?
我是说，你有一半负鼠血统就很糟糕了…
I mean, it's bad enough that your family is half possum and…
糟糕？
Bad enough?
我的家人才不糟糕
There is nothing bad about being part of my family.
我喜欢倒吊着
I like hanging by my tail.
如果你们这些天才叫正常，这个物种很快就得灭绝了
And if you geniuses are normal, this species is going to end up extinct.
你的物种才会先灭绝
Yeah, well, your species is going to be extinct first.
切 ！
Burn!
我们可是同一物种，天才们
We're the same species, genius.
什么？我再切
What? Double burn.
我的脚趾头又能动弹了
Hey, I can wiggle my toe again.
很重要的那个，去买菜都是它引的路
The important one, the little piggy who went to market.
等等！我又能说话了
Wait! I'm talking again.
我有那么多话要说，却说不出来
I had so many things trapped inside of me that I couldn't say.
比如‘嘿，我还活着！’
Like, "Hey, I'm not dead!"
还有‘为什么飓风有眼却没有耳朵？’
And, "Why does a hurricane have an eye but not an ear?"
我要把他扔下船，你们就当是个意外
L'll push him overboard. You guys say it was an accident.
我没意见，迭戈，你呢？迭戈？
I'm in. How about you, Diego? Diego?
放松，朋友！
Hey, relax, buddy!
疯子船长和他的漂流宠物园已经成历史了
Captain Crazy and his floating petting zoo are history.
振作点！我们终于能回家了！
Come on! We're finally heading home!
我也不知道自己怎么了
I don't know what's wrong with me.
我吃不下睡不着，也许我是生病了
I can't eat, can't sleep. Maybe I'm coming down with something.
我知道是什么病
I know what you've got.
还病得不轻哦
The L word.
麻风病？
Yeah, leprosy.
不是，希德，三个字对了
No, Sid, it's four letters.
但不是皮肤病，是心病
It starts with "L, " ends with "E."
心绞痛！
Lice!
不是，迭戈是得了相思病
No, Diego, my friend, is in love.
原来如此，他爱上了
Oh, yeah! Love.
你说我爱上了那个海盗？才不是
You mean with the pirate? No.
希拉让你寝食难安，承认吧
Shira's gotten under your skin. Come on, admit it.
死心眼的你
A rugged saber like you.
和更死心眼的她
A more rugged saber like her.
不不不，你们大错特错
No, no, no. You guys are dead wrong.
否认就是掩饰，你恋爱了，猫咪！
Denial is the clincher. You're in love, pussy cat!
迭戈和希拉，坐在树上
Diego and Shira Sitting in a tree.
亲-亲-亲-亲-亲
K-l-S-S-l-N-G.
成熟点，伙计们，成熟点
Real mature, guys. Real mature.
结婚生个虎宝宝，轻轻放在摇篮里
Then comes marriage Then comes a baby in the baby carriage.
吸吸小手指…
Sucking his thumb…
迭戈
Diego.
希拉？
Shira?
我想跟你走的
I wanted to come with you.
她真美
She's beautiful.
希德…
Sid…
我最喜欢邋里邋遢的树獭了
I adore a sloth who cares nothing about personal hygiene.
就是我啦，宝贝
That's me, baby.
奶奶
Granny.
来我这，奶奶
Come to me, Granny.
你好啊
Well, hello.
葡萄干越皱越甜，你越老越俏
The wrinklier the raisin, the sweeter the fruit.
奶奶喜欢
Granny likey.
奶奶非常喜欢
Granny likey very much.
- 大伙，你们注意到了没有？ - 曼尼…
- Guys, aren't you paying attention? - Manny…
- 曼尼，你在吗？ - 艾丽？
- Manny, are you there? - Ellie?
我们在这，曼尼
We're over here, Manny.
这边，爸爸
This way, Daddy.
我真的需要你
I really need you.
我知道，宝贝，待在那
I know, honey. Stay there.
我来了
I'm coming.
你是对的，曼尼，你一直是
You were right, Manny. You're always right.
不，听着，我…
No, look, I was…
等一下，艾丽从来不会对我说这个的
Wait a minute. Ellie would never say that.
曼尼？曼尼
Manny? Manny.
不，他们不是真的，他们是怪物！
No, they're not real. They're monsters!
他们是海妖，别听他们的！
They're sirens. Don't listen to them!
谁能将太阳升起，洒满晨露
Who can take the sunrise Sprinkle it with dew.
不！她们看起来像真的，可她们不是
No! They may look real, but they're not.
她们想把船撞毁
They're going to destroy the ship.
来啊，老虎，和我一起遨游
Come on, tiger. Swim with me.
希德…
Sid…
有点心给你吃
I have a snack for you.
她也会做饭
And she cooks, too.
希德，别！
Sid, no!
我们怎么在接吻？
Why are we kissing?
也许游艇出游就该浪漫点？
Because cruises are romantic?
迟上个五秒，我们就都死翘翘了
Five more seconds and we'd have been goners.
常联系哦
Call me.
给，宝贝
Here, girl.
给，珍珍
Here, Precious.
她以为她终于找到宠物了
She thinks she finally found her pet.
好孩子，给
Good girl. Here you go.
奶奶，你就不能用幻想的食物喂你那幻想的宠物吗？
Granny, can't you throw imaginary food to your imaginary pet?
已经够了
Enough already.
我们要随时了望家的方向
We need to keep a lookout for home.
别理他们，珍珍
Ignore them, Precious.
我就不理
I do.
一分钟不看着她都不行
You can't take your eyes off her for one minute.
是啊，就跟带小孩一样
Nope, it's like having a child.
只是没有任何乐趣
Only without any of the joy.
嘿，夸夸其谈的家伙们…
Hey, brain trust…
迎接撞击吧
brace for impact.
大伙看啊
Guys, look.
我们快到家了！
We're almost home!
- 伙计，我从没怀疑过你 - 我也是
- Buddy, I never doubted you. - Me either.
除了有那么几次，我以为我们要完蛋了
Except for the six or seven times I thought we were going to die.
怎么了，甜心？
What's wrong, sweetheart?
你有说过让自己追悔莫及的话吗？
You ever say something you knew you couldn't take back?
和路易斯有关？
Ls this about Louis?
我彻底搞砸了，妈妈
I messed up so bad, Mom.
没关系，难免的
It's okay. It happens.
毫无疑问，帅哥使人疯狂
Cute boys can whiplash your brain. No doubt about that.
但伊森和我不合适
But Ethan was the wrong guy.
你也发现了
And you figured it out.
你会知道该对路易斯说什么的
You'll know what to say to Louis.
怎么了？
What's going on?
陆桥
The land bridge.
塌掉了
It's gone.
我们被困住了
We're trapped!
但我们说好了在这里等爸爸，怎么办？
But we were supposed to meet Dad here. What are we going to do?
艾丽！
Ellie!
桃桃！
Peaches!
不，陆桥
Oh, no. The land bridge.
如果陆桥塌了…
But if it's gone…
- 我们怎么… - 希德！
- how are we going to… - Sid!
不，他们肯定在另外一边
No, they have to be on the other side.
曼尼，没有另外一边
Manny, there is no other side.
他们肯定在这
They have to be here.
艾丽！
Ellie!
桃桃
Peaches!
我在这！
I'm here!
拜托…
Please…
她肯定在这
she's got to be here.
爸爸！
Dad!
- 等等，你听到吗？ - 曼尼…
- Wait, did you hear that? - Manny…
不，我听到了，我听到了！
No, I heard something. I heard it!
- 那是？ - 桃桃！是她！
- Is that? - Peaches? There she is!
爸爸！
Dad!
我们来了，宝贝，别动！
We're coming, sweetie. Don't move!
爸爸！
Daddy!
桃桃！
Peaches!
欢迎回家，爸爸
Welcome home, Daddy.
放开我
Let go of me.
真巧啊
What are the odds?
我们正谈论你呢
We were just talking about you.
你喜欢这艘新船吗？我管她叫甜蜜复仇号
You like the new ship? I call her Sweet Revenge.
瞧瞧这，她们两个都落在我们手上了
And look here. We've got the catch du jour.
艾丽
Ellie.
我没事
I'm all right.
放了我女儿
Let my daughter go.
不要紧的
It's okay.
他要的是我，就让他来抓我吧
He wants me. And he's going to get me.
牺牲自己救女儿，多么感人
Sacrificing yourself for your daughter. How touching.
多么老套啊
How predictable.
过来换她吧
Now come and get her.
日安，朋友
Good day, mate.
记得我们吗？
You remember us?
我们是坏蛋
We're the bad guys.
好了，放了他们
All right, let them go.
不太可能
I don't think so.
你毁了我的一切
You destroyed everything I had.
我以牙还牙而已
I'm just returning the favor.
不！
No!
我警告过你
I warned you.
住手！
Stop!
放了猛犸象！
Let the mammoth go!
小样？
Weiner?
谁请来的肌肉男？
Who brought the muscle to the party?
路易斯，别逞强！
Louis, don't!
他在干嘛？他这是找死
What's he doing? He's going to get himself killed.
没关系，我能搞定他
It's okay, I can handle him.
多温馨啊，英雄救美
How cute, a hero.
那就看看你有多勇敢
Let's see what bravery gets you.
古普塔，把你的武器给他
Gupta, give the lad your weapon.
很高兴认识你，小子
Nice knowing you, kid.
亮招吧，英雄
Let's dance, hero.
别傻站着，抓住他！
Don't stand there like barnacles. Get him!
要去哪吗，朋友？
Oi, going somewhere, mate?
我来对付他
Let me at him.
有遗言吗？
Any last words?
珍珍！
Precious!
你能别再叫“珍珍”了吗？
Will you stop with the "Precious"?
妈呀
Mummy.
看来我们把他们吓跑了，对吧？
Well, I guess we showed them, huh?
- 珍珍！ - 那是你的宠物？
- Precious! - That's your pet?
也许奶奶也不是真的那么疯
Maybe that crazy old bat isn't that crazy after all.
不，她就是疯子
Nope, she's nuts.
还要我请你吗，小子？
You waiting for a formal invitation, fancy pants?
进来
Get in.
我会后悔的
I'm going to regret this.
炸弹来了！
Bombs away!
别像个胆小猫一样
Don't be a scaredy cat.
这比我还难闻
This smells worse than me.
珍珍，向北45度前进
Precious, set your flippers 45 degrees north.
奶奶不想再跑了
Granny's done running.
走开
Back off.
没事的，我跟你们一边的
It's okay, I'm on your side.
我就知道你是叛徒
I knew you were a traitor.
你生气的时候，鼻子扭扭最可爱
Your little bunny nose wiggles in the cutest way when you're mad.
什么？
What?
纳你的九条命来，猫咪
Your nine lives are over, kitty.
蠢兔子…
Silly rabbit…
海盗没好下场
piracy doesn't pay.
你真没意思，别这样
Hey, that's not cool. Come on, now.
谁有沐浴露吗？
Anyone have a body wipe?
省省吧你，情况怎样？
Suck it up, buttercup. How's it looking?
不太好，奶奶长官
Not good, Granny sir.
全速前进！
Full speed ahead!
潜水！
Dive, dive, dive!
开火！
Fire!
轰死你！
Booyah, baby!
太舒服了！
This feels so good!
谢谢，鲸鱼先生
Thank you, Mister Whale.
- 曼尼 - 希德！
- Hi, Manny. - Sid!
救命！
Help!
妈妈！
Mom!
别，桃桃，我去救你妈妈，你待着
No, Peaches, l'll get your mother. You stay there.
快点，曼尼
Hurry, Manny.
该算账了
Payback time.
曼尼！
Manny!
- 艾丽！ - 我能行，爸爸
- Ellie! - I got this, Dad.
桃桃，别！太危险了！
Peaches, no! Lt's too dangerous!
我有一半负鼠血统我怕谁！
Not if you're half-possum!
她成功了
She did it.
我女儿真的长大了
My daughter's all grown up.
这才是我的女儿
That's my girl.
我们得离开这
We need to get out of here.
走，快走，我来掩护
Go, go, I'm right behind you.
不！
No!
是我来‘掩护’你
I'm right behind you.
爸爸！
Dad!
不！
No!
你已经穷途末路了，曼尼
There's nowhere to run, Manny.
要知道，一海不容二主
You know, this ocean isn't big enough for the both of us.
别担心…
Don't worry…
等我把你压扁了，你就不占空间了
you won't take up much space once I flatten you.
我告诉过你，肥仔…
I told you, tubby…
你不该惹恼我这海上霸王
you shouldn't have messed with the Master of the Seas.
有时候，体重11吨也是有好处的！
You know, sometimes, it pays to weigh eleven tons!
不！
No!
一路顺风，猴仔！
Bon voyage, monkey boy!
有人召唤鲸鱼了吗？
Did somebody hail a whale?
你就是珍珍了
So, you must be Precious.
任务完成，奶奶
Mission accomplished, Granny.
谁说老太不能驾驶的？
Who says old ladies can't drive?
肚黑船长！
Oh, Captain Gutt!
我在！
That's me!
我们一起称霸四海吧
Let's rule the seas together.
遵命
Aye, aye.
爸爸！
Dad!
这个出场如何啊？
How's that for an entrance?
爸爸！
Dad!
曼尼
Manny.
我说了你爸不会抛弃我们的
I told you your father would never give up on us.
永远不会
Never.
实际上，我…
Hey, I actually…
希德…
You know, Sid…
你也不算一团糟
you're not such a screw-up.
- 真的吗？ - 真的
- Really? - Really.
你是英雄
You're a hero.
你也是，奶奶
You too, Granny.
谢了，姑娘
Thanks, lady.
还想要我加入你们吗？
So, still want me on your scurvy crew?
当然，欢迎加入
You bet. Welcome to our herd.
喂
Hey, you.
没想到你会为我挺身而出
I can't believe you did that for me.
谢谢
Thank you.
有人曾说，无论如何…
Someone once told me, no matter what…
都不能抛弃朋友
you never leave a friend behind.
我的牙都快被你们甜倒了
All this sweetness is going to rot my teeth.
如果我有的话
If I had any.
我们的家园没了
Our home is gone.
我们现在去哪？
Where do we go now?
妈妈也爱你！
Momma loves you, too!
- 我恨不得马上把这里探个究竟 - 是啊
- I can't wait to check this place out. - Yeah.
- 不好意思？ - 爸爸！
- Excuse me? - Dad!
你们下了船之后，我希望你们俩个都…
When you two get off this ship, I expect you both to…
玩得高兴
have fun.
你很勇敢，小样
You're a brave kid, Weiner.
等等，什么？
Wait, what?
你没听错，你们应该出去体验大千世界
You heard me. You two should go out and explore.
白天出去走走
Go where the day takes you.
但日落之前得回来
But be back before sunset.
日落后一小时可以吗？
An hour after sunset?
一分钟都不能迟
Yeah, not a minute later.
成交
Deal.
我爱你，爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我们和你们一道可以吗？
Okay if we hang with you guys?
当然
Sure.
我一直挺喜欢他的
I always liked him.
英雄路易斯，英勇无比
Louis the hero. Brave-a-licious.
她不再是我的那个小女孩了
She's not my little girl anymore.
别担心，会好起来的
And you're both going to be just fine.
我知道
I know.
你知道吗，希德？在这儿你找到了一个温暖的家
You know, Sidney? You've got yourself a nice family, here.
一个真正的家
A real family.
嗯，我很幸运
Yeah, I'm pretty lucky.
拿着，帮我嚼嚼这个狝猴桃
Here, chew this kiwi for me.
不用了
Never again.
看！
Ta-da!
- 你好，水手 - 哇！
- Hey, sailor. - Whoa!
欢迎，兄弟
Welcome, brother.
看，奎特兰蒂斯
Behold, Scratlantis.
不！
No!
停手！
Stop!
兄弟，超脱于本能欲望之上
Brother, rise above this base desire.
别再当一只低下的老鼠
Be more than a rodent.
我们，我们不是真正的一家人
We are, we are Not your ordinary fam-a, ma-lee.
但我们都同意
But we can all agree that.
我们，我们
We are, we are.
亲密无间
Close as close can be.
太亲密了！
Too close!
我们是
We are are are are are.
We are.
我们是
We are are are are are.
We are.
我们是
We are are are are are.
We are.
我们是
一家人
Family.
长相不同没关系，一切于我已完美
So it don't matter what it looks like We look perfect to me.
我们满满都是爱，我就是幸运星
We got every kind of love I feel so lucky indeed.
他们可以一直说，我也不介意
They can keep on talkin' lt don't matter to me.
因为我们是
'Cause we are, we are.
一家人
Family.
我们是
We are, we are.
火腿和芝士
Ham and cheese.
不对，是“我们是一家人”
No, it's, "We are family."
我们之间的联系将彼此拉得更紧
Okay so the links in our chain Makes us strain.
也使我们变得更坚强
But really they make us stronger.
拿什么也不换，妈妈
And I wouldn't replace not a thing Mother.
- 或爸爸 - 去吧，曼尼
- Or father. - Go, Manny.
因为我们
'Cause we.
因为我们来自四面八方
'Cause we come from everywhere.
共觅栖息之地
Searching for ones to care.
于是我们找到这里
Somehow we found it here.
我们找到了家园
We found us a home.
我们，我们不是真正的一家人
We are, we are Not your ordinary fam-a, ma-lee.
但我们都同意
But we can all agree that.
我们
We are, we are.
亲密无间
Close as close can be.
我们是
We are are are are are.
We are.
我们是
We are are are are are.
We are.
我们是
We are are are are are.
We are.
我们是
We are We are.
一家人
Family.
我们是
We are, we are.
火腿和芝士
Ham and cheese.